

# Mani Meskartehrani

Gmail ( (778) 361- 0725 Vancouver,BC,CA in LinkedIn



## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Detail-orientated, proactive and responsible engineer, with a get-it-done, on-time and high-quality product spirit. I am an aspiring frontend developer with 3 years of experience in the IT industry. Currently, I focus on learning NextJs and TypeScript. I typically use react.js and JavaScript to create components and user interfaces. In the end, I can help companies to develop more SEO-friendly websites.

## **SUMMARY OF SKILLS**

- Working experience with the most well-known Frontend library such as React.
- Experienced with programming languages and knowledge such as HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Familiar with website architecture and UX/UI best practices.
- Conducted responsive design and technical SEO.

#### **Key Skills**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP / CMS
- React
- Github

- Git
- TypeScript
- Technical SEO
- Responsive Design
- **REST API**

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Frontend Developer & SEO

IPM-IRNIC | Tehran, Iran

Jun 2018 - Jan 2020

- Conduct website optimization to increase reachability by resolving technical issues HTML/ CSS and JavaScript.
- Improved website API by changing XML coding to better performance in connectivity and accessibility.
- Modified website frontend and planning to use react.js for improving site speed and UX.

### Frontend Web Developer | Volunteer

Jun 2014 - Jan 2015

Kaj Real Estate | Tehran, Iran

• Designed and developed Front-end and Back-end of the store's website using HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript technology.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Business Administration | Digital Marketing

Oct 2020 - Jan 2022

University of Canada West - BC, CA

**Bachelor of Engineering** | Software

Sep 2007 – July 2012

University of Guilan - Rasht, Iran